<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UnGrad</title>
    <description>Learn the correct way!</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 16:14:26 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 16:14:26 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Transfer Learning Deep Dive</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;PyTorch is quickly becoming one of the most popular deep learning frameworks around, as well as a must-have skill in your artificial intelligence tool kit. It’s gained admiration from industry leaders due to its deep integration with Python; its integration with top cloud platforms, including Amazon SageMaker and Google Cloud Platform; and its computational graphs that can be defined on the fly. In this course, join our instructor as he dives into the basics of deep learning using PyTorch. Starting with a working image recognition model, he shows how the different components fit and work in tandem—from tensors, loss functions, and autograd all the way to troubleshooting a PyTorch network.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/transfer-learning-deep-dive/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/transfer-learning-deep-dive/</guid>
        
        <category>data science</category>
        
        <category>python</category>
        
        
        <category>Transfer Learning</category>
        
        <category>Machine Learning</category>
        
        <category>Artificial Intelligence</category>
        
        <category>PyTorch</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Text analytics and predictions using Python</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Text is a rich source of insights for businesses. Websites, social media, emails, and chats all contain valuable customer data. But to reap the rewards, you need to be able to analyze large amounts of unstructured text. Text mining is an essential skill for anyone working in big data and data science. This course teaches text-mining techniques to extract, cleanse, and process text using Python and the scikit-learn and nltk libraries. Our Indian instructor explains how to perform text analytics using popular techniques like word cloud and sentiment analysis. He then shows how to make predictions with text data using clustering, classification, and recommendations—otherwise known as predictive text. Along the way, he introduces important text analytics concepts such as lemmatization and n-grams.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/text-analytics/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/text-analytics/</guid>
        
        <category>data science</category>
        
        <category>python</category>
        
        
        <category>Data Science</category>
        
        <category>Machine Learning</category>
        
        <category>Artificial Intelligence</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Building a recommendation system with Python ML</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover how to use Python—and some essential machine learning concepts—to build programs that can make recommendations. In this hands-on course, our instructor covers the different types of recommendation systems out there, and shows how to build each one. She helps you learn the concepts behind how recommendation systems work by taking you through a series of examples and exercises. Once you’re familiar with the underlying concepts, Lillian explains how to apply statistical and machine learning methods to construct your own recommenders. She demonstrates how to build a popularity-based recommender using the Pandas library, how to recommend similar items based on correlation, and how to deploy various machine learning algorithms to make recommendations. At the end of the course, she shows how to evaluate which recommender performed the best.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/recommendation-system/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/recommendation-system/</guid>
        
        <category>data science</category>
        
        <category>python</category>
        
        
        <category>Data Science</category>
        
        <category>Machine Learning</category>
        
        <category>Artificial Intelligence</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Python for data-science (Part 2)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In this course, the instructor takes you step by step through a practical data science project: building machine learning models that can generate predictions and recommendations and automate routine tasks. Along the way, she shows how to perform linear and logistic regression, use K-means and hierarchal clustering, identify relationships between variables, and use other machine learning tools such as neural networks and Bayesian models. You should walk away from this training with hands-on coding experience that you can quickly apply to your own data science projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/python-data-science-pt2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/python-data-science-pt2/</guid>
        
        <category>data science</category>
        
        <category>python</category>
        
        
        <category>Data Science</category>
        
        <category>Machine Learning</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Python for data-science (Part 1)</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Python for Data Science Essential Training is one of the most popular data science courses at UnGrad Learning. It has now been updated and expanded to two parts—for even more hands-on experience with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this course, instructor takes you step by step through a practical data science project: a web scraper that downloads and analyzes data from the web. Along the way, she introduces techniques to clean, reformat, transform, and describe raw data; generate visualizations; remove outliers; perform simple data analysis; and generate interactive graphs using the Plotly library. You should walk away from this training with basic coding experience that you can take to your organization and quickly apply to your own custom data science projects..&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/python-data-science-pt1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/python-data-science-pt1/</guid>
        
        <category>data science</category>
        
        <category>python</category>
        
        
        <category>Data Science</category>
        
        <category>Machine Learning</category>
        
        <category>Python</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Amazon EC2 Deep Dive</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2) provides secure, resizable compute capacity in the cloud. You can quickly increase or decrease capacity as your requirements change—only paying for the capacity you need now. In this course, instructor Shyam Raj helps you deepen your understanding of Amazon EC2. Learn how to attach Elastic Block Store (EBS) volumes to your instances and enable features such as encryption and snapshots, which help you back up the data on your volumes. Shyam also provides coverage of Amazon Machine Images (AMI) and explores the key features, working mechanism, and use cases for T2 and T3 instances. Plus, discover the options for Amazon EC2 networking and explore purchasing options, such as on-demand versus reserved and spot instances, that help you maximize your budget without sacrificing power.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/amazon-ec2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/amazon-ec2/</guid>
        
        <category>backend</category>
        
        <category>devops</category>
        
        
        <category>Amazon EC2</category>
        
        <category>DevOps</category>
        
        <category>Backend</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
